Thomas J. Dodd Papers
© 2004 University of Connecticut
Thomas J. Dodd Papers.
1919-1971.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Center.
Dodd, Thomas J.
220 linear feet.
The Thomas J. Dodd Papers illuminate the diverse public life of a self-styled crusader. The collection consists primarily of material from Dodd's Senate years (1959-1971) and the Nuremberg war crimes trial before the International Military Tribunal from 1945-1946.
MSS19940065S12
Arrangement
Series I: Outgoing Correspondence (1959-1970)
Series II: Subject Files (1959-1969)
Series III: Administrative and Legislative Files (1949-1971).
Series IV: Investigative Files (1956-1970)
Series V: Foreign Travel Files (1954-1969)
Series VI: Campaign Files (1949-1970)
Series VII: Nuremberg Trial ( 1919-1995 )
Series VIII: Personal Papers (1920-1971)
Series IX: Scrapbooks (1935-1971)
Series X: Photographs (1920-1970)
Series XI: Awards and Memorabilia (1926-1970)
Series XII: Audiovisual Materials (1946-1969) consists primarily of sound tape, film, and videotape of Dodd speeches and other public appearances from 1947-1967. One videotape, "The Crusader From Connecticut" (1964), provides a biographical summary of Dodd's life and career prior to his second Senate term. This series is arranged in chronological order, except where the different formats of audiovisual items dictated other boxing arrangements.
Return to Thomas J. Dodd Papers.
Restrictions on Access
As a preservation measure, use of film reels requires production of viewing copies. Original films are stored on cores. The gauge of the films is 16mm. Requests to use the materials should be directed to the Curator.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Kosovo and Beyond 1994-0065.vr1
Detailed Description
- Series XII: Audio Visual Materials, undated, 1947-1967
  - Subseries A: Films, undated, 1959-1969
    - Documentary film on Nuremberg Trial, undated (Other 1994-0065.mp1)
    - Thomas Dodd interview with Senator John F. Kennedy, undated (Other 1994-0065.mp2)
      2 reels
    - Washington, D.C. scenes, undated (Other 1994-0065.mp14)
      B/W, Sound
    - Thomas Dodd interview with Senator Paul Douglas, undated (Other 1994-0065.mp16)
      B/W, Sound, Sen Dodd Lab #2129
    - Thomas Dodd and Mr. Symington, undated (Other 1994-0065.mp17)
      B/W, Sound, Symington #2128
    - Thomas Dodd interview with Senator Hubert Humphrey, undated (Other 1994-0065.mp18)
      B/W, Sound, Humphrey #2127
    - T.V. Reudell, undated (Other 1994-0065.mp20)
      B/W, Sound, Dodd film #5988
    - Thomas Dodd and Richard Rendell, undated (Other 1994-0065.mp31)
      B/W, Sound, Dodd film #5988 - 4 copies
    - Thomas Dodd with Carey Cronan, undated (Other 1994-0065.mp32)
      B/W, Sound, Dodd film #2953
    - Thomas Dodd with Don Larabee, undated (Other 1994-0065.mp33)
      B/W, Sound, Dodd film #3012 - 2 copies
    - Thomas Dodd with Henry M. Jackson, undated (Other 1994-0065.mp34)
      B/W, Sound, Dodd film #2748 - 2 copies
    - Thomas Dodd interview with Senator Lyndon Johnson, 1959 August 12 (Other 1994-0065.mp3)
      B/W, Sound, Dodd film #3363
    - WNBC-TV, 1960 January 24 (Other 1994-0065.mp35)
    - Thomas Dodd Washington Review program #6, 1961 (Other 1994-0065.mp23)
    - Thomas Dodd and Carey Cronan, 1961 (Other 1994-0065.mp30)
      4 reels, B/W, Sound, Dodd film #5149
    - Thomas Dodd Washington Review program #4 interview with Buck Griffin, 1961 March 6 (Other 1994-0065.mp24)
    - Thomas Dodd Washington Review program, 1961 March 26 (Other 1994-0065.mp13)
    - Thomas Dodd Washington Review program #5 interview with Abraham Ribicoff, 1961 April 10 (Other 1994-0065.mp25)
      2 copies, B/W, Sound
    - Thomas Dodd with Eugene Zuckert, 1961 May 7 (Other 1994-0065.mp27)
      B/W, Sound, Dodd film #5274
    - Thomas Dodd Washington Review program #9 with Carey Cronan, 1961 May 22 (Other 1994-0065.mp12)
    - W.R. ["Washington Review"?], 1961 September 25 (Other 1994-0065.mp37)
    - Thomas Dodd interview with Senator Mike Mansfield, W.R. Senator Dodd #5, 1962 April 2 (Other 1994-0065.mp15)
    - Thomas Dodd, 1962 April 16 (Other 1994-0065.mp21)
    - Thomas Dodd and Senator Kenneth Keating, 1962 May (Other 1994-0065.mp26)
    - Thomas Dodd interview with Father Matthew Menger, 1962 May 19 (Other 1994-0065.mp22)
    - Thomas Dodd interview with Sergeant Shriver (Peace Corps), 1963 (Other 1994-0065.mp4)
    - Thomas Dodd interview with Capt. Anderson of National Service Corps, 1963 (Other 1994-0065.mp6)
      B/W, Sound, Dodd film #9065
    - Thomas Dodd interview with Werner Von Braun, 1963 (Other 1994-0065.mp7)
      B/W, Sound, Dodd film #8118/5885
    - "Dodd and Humphrey (Civil Rights)", 1963 June 20 (Other 1994-0065.mp5)
    - Thomas Dodd interview with Chester Bowles, 1963 June 6 (Other 1994-0065.mp8)
      B/W, Sound, Dodd film #8665
    - Thomas Dodd interview with Mr. Burdick concerning nuclear test ban, 1963 July 3 (Other 1994-0065.mp9)
      B/W, Sound, Dodd film #8660
    - Thomas Dodd interview with Senator Paul Douglas for Captive Nations Week, 1963 July 16 (Other 1994-0065.mp10)
      2 reels, B/W, Sound, Dodd film #8872
    - Thomas Dodd civil rights interview with Hubert Humphrey, 1964 March 25 (Other 1994-0065.mp11)
    - Thomas Dodd and Russell Long, 1966 January 19 (Other 1994-0065.mp28)
      B/W, Sound, Dodd film #28786
    - Thomas Dodd interview with Alan Boyd, 1966 February 1 (Other 1994-0065.mp19)
      B/W, Sound, Dodd film #2889
    - Thomas Dodd and Esther Peterson, 1966 March 2 (Other 1994-0065.mp29)
      B/W, Sound, Dodd film #3053
    - W.R. ["Washington Review"?], 1969 (Other 1994-0065.mp36)
      There are approximately an additional 26 unidentified film reels in the Thomas J. Dodd Papers. Some of which contain footage of Senator Dodd at a desk often interviewing certain people or depicting several outdoor miscellaneous scenes. Most of these films do not have dates, however the range of dates appears to be from 1959 to 1969. The majority of these films are 16mm, black & white, with sound. There are a few color films.
  - Subseries B: Sound recordings, undated, 1946-1967
    - Unidentified (2 reels), undated
    - "Hotbed of Hatred" broadcast (3 reels), undated
    - Interview with Senators Eugene McCarthy, Mike Mansfield, Paul Douglas, Joseph Clark, and William Proxmire (reel), undated
    - "Pep Pills" interview on Walter Cronkite show (reel), undated
    - Thomas Dodd interview with Senator Hubert Humphrey (reel), undated
    - Thomas Dodd with Congressman George Meader (reel), undated
    - Nuremberg International Military Tribunal verdicts, 1946 Oct 17
    - "Flexograph" discs of office dictation (7), undated, 1947-1948
    - Thomas Dodd interview on "Juke Box Jingles" broadcast (331/3 rpm), 1952 December 5
    - Thomas Dodd interview on "Cracker Barrel" broadcast(331/3 rpm), 1953 Feb 9
    - Thomas Dodd campaign songs (78 rpm), 1956
    - Nominating speeches at Connecticut Democratic Convention (331/3 rpm; 4 discs), 1956 July 7
    - Thomas Dodd acceptance speech for Democratic nomination to U.S. Senate (331/3 rpm; 2 discs), 1956 July 7
    - Senators Stuart Symington, John F. Kennedy, Hubert Humphrey, Paul Douglas, and Lyndon Johnson supporting Thomas Dodd's Senate candidacy, 1958 Aug 15
    - Thomas Dodd speeches (WTIC; 6 reels), 1958 October 1 - 29
    - Thomas Dodd interview with Senator Lyndon Johnson (reel), 1959 August 12
    - Thomas Dodd bi-weekly program #1 (reel), 1960 January 18
    - Thomas Dodd bi-weekly program #2 (reel), 1960 February 4
    - Thomas Dodd bi-weekly program #3 (reel), 1960 February 18
    - Thomas Dodd bi-weekly program #4 (reel), 1960 April 28
    - Thomas Dodd bi-weekly program #6 (reel), 1960 May 23
    - Thomas Dodd bi-weekly program #7 (reel), 1960 June 7
    - Thomas Dodd bi-weekly program #8 ( reel), 1960 June 21
    - "Election 60 Spotlight": Thomas Dodd - Prescott Bush debate, 1960 October 16
    - Thomas Dodd "Washington Review" program #1 (reel), 1961 January 23
    - Thomas Dodd "Washington Review" program #2 (reel), 1961 February 6
    - Thomas Dodd "Washington Review" program #3 (reel), 1961 February 21
    - Thomas Dodd "Washington Review" program #4 (reel), 1961 March 6
    - Thomas Dodd interview with Werner von Braun (Edison Voicewriter flexible red disc), 1961 August 10
    - Thomas Dodd appearance on Mark Evans show titled "Opinion in the Capital" (reel), 1962 August 5
    - "Capitol Cloakroom" program, 1963 September 5
    - "Hello Lyndon" campaign song (45rpm), 1964
    - Thomas Dodd campaign radio commercials (331/3 rpm), 1964
    - "Leading Question" program, 1964 May 12
    - Unidentified (reel), 1966 April 1
    - "Powell Dodd Charge" broadcast (reel), ca. 1967
    - "Retractions": dubbings of Roy Elwell and Thomas Dodd (reel), 1967 June 21, 1967 July 6
  - Subseries C: Video recordings, undated, 1956-1965
    - Thomas Dodd speech at Connecticut Democratic Convention (VHS), 1956
    - "Crusader From Connecticut" (2"), 1964
    - Senator Thomas Dodd (2"), 1964 October 26
    - Senator Thomas Dodd (2"), 1964 November 2
    - "Meet the Senators" broadcast (VHS), 1959 January 11
    - Thomas Dodd discussion of German rearmament, civil rights, and other issues (VHS), 1959 April
    - Hon. Senator Thomas Dodd and Victor Borge [videorecording]: (Washington, D.C., 1965), 1965 (Box Dodd Video 249)
      Senator Dodd introduces Victor Borge as an outstanding citizen of Connecticut and then interviews Borge on his opinions of the United States and the current state of the world (circa 5 minutes).
    - "VIP - Senator Dodd" broadcast, 1959 May 10
    - Thomas Dodd bi-weekly programs #1-8 (VHS), 1960
    - "Washington Review" programs (VHS), 1961 January - April
    - Thomas Dodd interview with Senator Paul Douglas interview for Captive Nations Week (VHS), 1963 July 16
    - "Crusader From Connecticut" (VHS), 1964
  - Return to Thomas J. Dodd Papers.